Okay, so in this video
then, we will just briefly
talk about some of the
ITTOs of cost management.
Again, just want to remind you,
don't try to memorize all of these ITTOs,
just have a decent understanding of them,
right?
You know, you don't need to
memorize them, just make sure
that you just have a, you know,
just a relative understanding.
Also, as a review, remember, an output is
some form of artifact usually.
this is the project document, the artifact
that we are trying to create.
An input is an artifact that we are
reviewing, right?
We are considering we are reviewing a
starting point.
It doesn't always have to be an artifact.
For example, most of the inputs will see
are EFs, Enterprise Environmental Factors.
Not all EFs are artifacts, right?
But this is something that
we're going to be considering
or something that we're
going to be reviewing.
And then a tool and technique is,
this is what we need to utilize.
This is what we need to do.
Tool and technique is usually some form of
action.
This is what we're going to do, some
kind of task that we're going to perform.
And if it is a document, it's
a document that we're going
to utilize, right, in order to
create our output artifact.
All right, now, just like every process
that I've been mentioning, right,
or every knowledge area from scope
management downwards, right, in the process.
process grid, right, the first process is
always plan knowledge area management,
right?
So in this case, we're talking about the
cost management, right?
So cost management knowledge area, so
plan cost management is the first process.
And what are we creating?
What artifact are we creating in plan cost
management?
We're creating the cost management plan,
right?
The cost management plan is documenting
how, right?
In any of these first, you
know, the first processes,
plan management processes,
we're documenting procedures.
We're documenting in this case,
how costs are going to be estimated and
monitored and controlled,
what formulas are we
going to use, what
conventions are we going to use?
And that's all documented in the cost
management plan.
Again, covered in a separate video,
right?
So all of these key
artifacts and tools and
techniques, they're all
covered in a separate video.
Now, estimating costs, this process called
estimate cost, refers to estimating costs
of individual activities, or it could be
work packages, right, cost of individual
activities, work packages, or even just
individual components of the project.
So we need to understand the cost of each
individual component of the project,
right, before we can come up with the
overall budget, right?
So we can aggregate all of these costs to
come up with.
the overall budget, right?
We don't just first come up with a budget
and then work backwards in order to figure
out what individual components are going
to cost.
In reality, a lot of time that is what
happens, right?
A lot of times in reality, your
senior management will just
set a budget for the project
and a deadline for the project.
And it'll be some unrealistic budget,
some unrealistic deadline.
And, you know, as a project manager, you're
kind of like, what are they thinking?
We're not going to be able to meet this.
And that's exactly why PMI is setting the
standard here.
PMI is stating that you don't just take
your senior management's
word for it, right?
When they're setting some
budget or timeline, what
you have to do is you
utilize subject matter experts.
right, the people that are
performing the work should
be the ones that are
estimating the work, right?
So, utilize those subject matter experts
to come up with a budget and the timeline.
And so that's a correct approach.
So the correct approach is first to
estimate the cost of individual activities
and individual components
of the project and then
aggregate those to come
up with the overall budget.
And that's what this estimate cost process
refers to.
So, cost of individual estimates.
So that's what the cost estimate,
the output then, so the output then,
this is the artifact we're creating is the
cost estimate.
Basis of estimate is basically how we came
up with that cost estimate, right,
and then the starting point, right,
our input, our starting point,
what do we need to review, right?
Well, we need to review the procedures,
right, the cost management procedures,
how will we going to estimate
the cost, and then also,
you know, factors that's
going to impact the cost.
such as quality.
Quality is a direct cost to your project,
right?
Resources are a direct cost to your
project, right?
And as a schedule, direct cost to your
project.
So again, all the important artifacts and
tools we have separate
videos in each of these.
And then these are the different tools and
techniques.
Notice these tools and techniques are also
shared with schedule management.
So again, each of these
tools and techniques
we're going to be
discussing in separate videos.
Now, once we have identified or we've
estimated the cost of each individual
component on the project, now we can
aggregate those to come up with the
overall budget, and that's what this
process refers to, determine budget.
And the budget for the project,
the project manager's budget, is something
called the cost baseline, that again
covered in a separate video, and then
funding requirements
at each of various points
along the project, what funding is needed.
Notice one of the key tools and
techniques, cost aggregation.
That's what I just mentioned here.
You need to aggregate, add up all of the
cost to come up with the overall budget.
Now, cost aggregation also
goes one step further in the sense
that it rolls up each layer of
the work breakdown structure.
Again, we have separate videos on those.
We'll talk about contingency reserves,
risk reserves.
Contingency reserves are also a direct
cost to your project.
So we'll talk about those in separate
videos as well.
Right.
And then the last process is control cost.
Control cost basically means monitoring
controlling.
This is a monitoring controlling process.
As with all monitoring controlling
processes, what are we doing?
We are comparing actual results with our
plan.
Our actual results is workforce data,
raw observation.
We're comparing it with our plan and to
come up with our work performance
information, right, which is the
interpretation.
So this is what it means.
Right.
So in this case, we're talking about the
cost.
So the work performance information means
how much over budget
or under budget we are.
So our work performance data is our raw
observation actual result.
Right.
So in an example, workforce data could be,
you know, $20,000.
So we have spent $20,000, right,
doing this activity.
That's my raw observation, right?
How much should I have spent?
I should have spent $18,000.
That's my plan.
So my work performance information tells
me I'm $2,000 over budget.
I went $2,000 over budget.
And that's what workforce information is,
right?
And all these earned value formulas,
right, which are covered in separate
videos, right, they all relate to work
performance information.
Remember, information is always,
right, this is what it means, you're
comparing, actually, results, which is the
workforce as data from executing.
Workformist data always comes from
executing the actual results.
You're comparing it with your plan to get
your interpretation.
What does it actually mean?
Alright, so these are
then, there's just a brief
summary then of the
ITTOs of cost management.